Rebecca Mutek

PROFILE

Works at Aon as an executive liability insurance broker specializing in publicly traded companies; current role requires excellent communication and listening skills to deliver superior client results. Attended Actualize coding bootcamp with the goal of transitioning into a career as a developer in order to solve problems and provide an excellent user experience.

PROJECTS

Oy'ster

Oy'ster is a social network for individuals who love, enjoy and are enthusiastic about oysters. Users can post reviews, browse restaurants, find oyster specific specials and receive recommendations. Restaurant roulette is a feature which asks the user for several parameters and then matches them with a restaurant and a specific oyster. As users post reviews they become eligible for exclusive events and special offers.

Oy'ster was built using Ruby on Rails and VueJS. Oy'ster was created to share and track oysters enjoyed over a lifetime for those who like to live life on the half shell.

Visit Oy'ster at https://shrouded-basin-69875.herokuapp.com/

(Please note that several bugs are still being worked out and I am happy to demo the application locally on my laptop)

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Web Developer

The Difference Engine | Chicago, IL | 2017 - Present

- Develops an e-commerce web application for a local business in an agile environment using Ruby on Rails and React
 - The application is being developed from scratch which increased the complexity of the project due to the numerous considerations regarding how the application should be structured
- Uses Trello to organize backlog, sprints, code in development, code under review, code ready for demo and deployed
- Exercises communication and consensus building skills when developing in a team environment to ensure all team members understand the various features being created simultaneously
- Requests and incorporates client feedback throughout the development process
- Writes Rspec tests to challenge each piece of code before pushing to Github

Full-Stack Web Developer

Actualize | Chicago, IL | 2017 - 2017

- Attended a 17-week full-stack web development training learning Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, VueJS and SQL
- Contributed to a team resume app project by using an API our team created to pull data into a resume webpage; used VueJS and a Wrapbootstrap theme to display the data
- Learned to pair program
- Built a fully functional web app, Oy'ster, from scratch
- Proactively furthered knowledge of computer science and data structures by reading Code: The Hidden Language of Computer Hardware

Senior Broker

Aon | Chicago, IL | 2014 - Present

- Responsible for project planning which includes collaborating with interdisciplinary team members and clients to establish goals and objectives specific to each client needs
- Proactively provides updates to clients along the project timeline and welcomes feedback to ensure
 desired results are achieved within the predetermined deadline
- Prioritizes workflow to ensure all project components are complete before deadlines
- Facilitates new business by proactively identifying account penetration opportunities

SKILLS

JavaScript

Ruby

Rails

HTML CSS

Git

. .

VueJS

React SQI

PostgreSQL

Adobe Illustrator CC

EDUCATION

Actualize

Full-Stack Web Developer | 2017

Temple University

Bachelors of Business Administration, Risk Management and Insurance | Cum Laude | 2010 - 2014

COMMUNITY

Temple University Alumni Association

Temple University Alumni Board Young Alumni Chair 2014 - Present

Lincoln Park Community Shelter

Volunteer

2016 - Present

WITS (Working in the Schools)

Student Mentor 2014 - 2016

CONTACT

Chicago, IL

Mutek.b@gmail.com

(215) 595-6395

github.com/Rmutek

linkedin.com/in/rebecca-mutek

medium.com/@RMutek

Website https://rmutek.github.io